Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to create platforms that the player can jump and stand
on.
To get started, go over to the image folder and briefly close on raw engine attached.
In this course lecture, I'm going to make sure to include these two images, platform one and platform
to select both of them and drag them into your folder.
Once you've done this, select both images and apply paper to the texture settings.
Then with both images selected, right click and go Sprite actions and go create Sprite.
Then if we go over to our item folder, we are going to create a new blueprint for our platform.
If we just right click and Go Blueprint class, select actor and call this platform underscore beep.
If we open this up.
Unlike opponent go ad and look for paper Sprite.
Under source spread look for platform one and just selector.
It's kind of small.
So under scale.
Make it have a size of eight.
So the way we're going to create this platform, my player character is going to be able to jump up
from underneath the platform.
And then when they jump and then on the platform, we're going to enable the collision of this platform
so my character can stand on it.
To make the system, we're going to need to go to add and look for box collision.
Place this collision kind of a bit above the platform.
And expand it in the x axis.
So the edges of the sprite match the box.
Just so that we can visually see our box in the game under details, look for hidden in game and just
make sure this is unchecked.
Now, if we just go over to the event graph and delete event activity, an overlap and event take event
we can play.
We're going to make it to our paper.
Sprite has no collision.
So if we drag in our papers right, drag up here and look for collision enabled.
And we want to select this one set collision enabled and make sure the new type is no collision.
So as soon as the game starts, we'll make our paper sprite type have no collision.
Then, if our player character overlaps this box, that basically means that on top of the platform.
And so we're going to enable the collision of this platform.
So if I scroll down and go to on component, we can overlap.
If this begins to overlap with another actor, if that actor is equal to our player character.
So I'm going to look for my player character.
Then we're going to do a brunch.
And enable the collision of our paper sprite.
So our drug in my paper Sprite and set its collision.
And I'll say it's collision to be collision enabled and just connect us into here.
If my player character ever leaves this platform, that kind of means that we should turn off the box
collision so that they can jump and land on this platform again.
So if I go back to my event graph and select the box, scroll down and go to UN component and overlap,
We can just copy all the notes here.
And face them here.
So when I play, I got to leave this platform.
We'll turn the collision of this off.
So we can compile and test this all out.
So I'm going to drag dragging my platform.
And we've got to lay out 20 maybe waxes.
And let's go play.
So if I jump up underneath the platform.
I kind of get stuck, so I'm going to actually place my box a bit higher.
So it looks like my plane got stuck when the collision was turning on.
So if we just move this a bit higher, this may take some experimentation.
So it could play.
I jump?
Okay.
So when I jumped and I got through, it turned the collision of this platform on.
If I go off this, I can do the same thing and do it again.
Okay, let's fix a couple of things.
It kind of looks a bit jittery when I initially land on the platform.
There are two ways I can fix this.
The first way is if I go over to my player blueprint.
And if we select the spring arm, scroll down and just enable this cam like.
If I go compile and play, the camera is now going to have a bit of a lagging effect to it, and this
will make it so things appear a bit smoother.
So now if I jump on this platform, you can see you didn't really notice that that that much.
The second way we can fix this is if I open up my platform blueprint and go over to the bit where we
enable creation for our paper spray.
Before we do this, we can have a short delay and that will kind of make things look a bit smoother.
So if I just drag up here and look forward today and just go compile now, let go play and I jump up
on this platform, it looks kind of smooth.
So now we have this platform that my player character can jump up from underneath.